Guide to the Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Photographs PHOTOS.265
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Photographs
1957-2001
1980-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Federation of School Administrators. Local 1, Council of Supervisors and Administrators (New York, N.Y.)
Logan, Ernest
PHOTOS.265
13.5 Linear Feet in 14 boxes
The Council of School Supervisors and Administrators (formerly the Council of Supervisors and Administrators) represents principals and other categories of supervisory/administrative personnel in the New York City school system. It had its origins in a number of separate and relatively powerless associations representing supervisors, and took its present form, as a union chartered by the AFL-CIO, in the aftermath of the crises associated with decentralization and community control of schools and the teachers' strike of 1967-1968. The collection consists of 13 linear feet of photographs, negatives, and contact sheets that span 1957 to 2001 and come mainly from the files of the union's newspaper, CSA News. NOTE: This collection is stored offsite, and advance notice is required for use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was separated from the Council of School Supervisors Records (WAG 269), which were donated by Ernest Logan (CSA President) on behalf of the Council of School Supervisors and Administrators, in 2007. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.231, 2007.007, and NPA.2008.040.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Council of School Supervisors and Administrators (formerly the Council of Supervisors and Administrators) represents principals and other categories of supervisory/administrative personnel in the New York City school system. Its origins are in the post-World War II years, when supervisors in various categories (including assistant superintendents, principals, assistant principals, chairmen of departments, junior principals and principals of youth and adult centers) were represented by a number of separate, and relatively powerless, associations. Eleven of these associations came together in 1961 to form a Council of Supervisory Associations of the Public Schools of New York City. The Council (aka CSA) took its present form, as a union chartered by the AFL-CIO, in the aftermath of the crises associated with decentralization and community control of schools and the teachers' strike of 1967-1968.
In recent decades the CSA has functioned as a fully-fledged trade-union, aggressively defending staffing, salary and benefits levels and tenure for supervisors; managing a Welfare Fund; lobbying on all legislative matters affecting public education (often in cooperation with the United Federation of Teachers and other public employee unions); providing educational and training opportunities for members; raising issues of workplace health and safety; and creating a more than 9,000-strong retirees' chapter. The union has also steadily expanded its outreach efforts, both to members and to the general public, through its publications such as its newspaper, CSA News, whose longtime news editor, Charnia Adelman, was largely responsible for the preservation and arrangement of most of the photographs in the CSA Photographs Collection.
Scope and Content Note
The small portion of the collection that is arranged by subject includes images of a miscellany of various events, conventions, meetings, schools, strikes, demonstrations, rallies, picket lines and a Labor Day parade, shot between 1957 and 2000, as well as portraits of individuals, including CSA leaders such as Jack Zuckerman, Donald Singer, and Peter O'Brien. The bulk of the collection, however, consists of images published, or selected for possible publication, in the union's newspaper, CSA News, for its volumes 8 through 34 (between 1974 and 2001). These are arranged by volume number (within print and contact sheet and negative series), with little or no description of their contents. Although most of the contact sheets in the CSA News series have corresponding negatives, and the series include some prints with matching negatives, it is doubtful that these files contain all of the images published in CSA News.
NOTE: This collection is stored offsite, and advance notice is required for use.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically and chronologically. The Collection is organized into 5 series: I. Prints and Contact Sheets--Subjects; 1957-2000, II. Prints--for CSA News, 1974-2001; Series III. Negatives—Subjects, 1973-1990; Series IV. Negatives--for CSA News, 1979-2001; V. Oversized - Undated.
Series I, Prints and Contact Sheets—Subject Files, consists of miscellaneous topics arranged in alphabetical order; Series II, Prints--for CSA News, consists of photographs shot for, gathered for, and/or published for the Council's official newspaper (earlier known as CSA Newsletter) for volumes published between 1974 and 2001, arranged in chronological order. Series III, Negatives--Subject Files, is arranged in alphabetical order and consists of a small number of images, mainly of conventions, most of which have corresponding contact sheets in Series I. Series IV, Negatives--for CSA News, consists of negatives that match prints from volumes in Series II, from 1979-2001, with the exception of 1998-1999, V. Series V, Oversized, includes panoramic group portraits and mounted photomontages.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Council of School Supervisors and Administrators Records (WAG 269).
Negatives (photographic); Contact sheets.; New York (N.Y.).; Black-and-white photographs.; Zuckerman, Jacob (Jack); Singer, Donald; O'Brien, Peter S.; American Federation of School Administrators. Local 1, Council of Supervisors and Administrators (New York, N.Y.); Logan, Ernest
- Series I: Prints and Contact Sheets, 1957-2000
  - Addleston, Lorraine: Scrapbook, Undated; 1957-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO Convention, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AFL-CIO Course, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anker, Irving, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Drug Campaign - Poster Contest, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Association of Assistant Principals (AAP) Convention Photos (includes pictures of key CSA founders), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Association of Assistant Principals (AAP) Convention Photos - Statler-Hilton (includes pictures of key CSA founders), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Automotive High School/Grady, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Awards Dinner, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Education: Toys for Tots, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, Jun 17, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boat Ride, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - CPAC Breakfast, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Coalition Meeting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Conference, Nov 13, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Convention, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Convention, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Convention, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Convention, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Convention, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Convention: Prints and Contact Sheets, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Convention, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Convention, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Convention, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Convention: Prints and Contact Sheets, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets and Prints, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets and Prints, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets and Prints, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets and Prints, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Convention: Prints and Contact Sheets, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Convention: Prints and Contact Sheets, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Convention: Prints and Contact Sheets, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Convention: Contact Sheets, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Convention: Prints, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Convention Retreat, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - CSA Contract Signing, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - CSA - Early History, 1959; 1966-1970; 1960s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Day Care, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: City Hall Rally, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: CSA Demonstration in Support of Newark Teachers, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Labor Day Parade, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Miscellaneous, 1980; 1990s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Protest Letters to Chancellor Re: Lack of Contract, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Rally on Livingston Street, Aug 31, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Rally to Protest Dist. 1 Purge, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Save Our Schools Rally, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Screen Actors Guild Picket Line (Jason Robards, Mickey Rooney, Henry Nagler), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: Strike, Sep 1, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Demonstrations, Rallies, Picket Lines, Parades: United Federation of Teachers (UFT) Para-Professionals Demonstration, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - District Chairmen's Conference, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - District Chairmen's Conference, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - District Chairs (High School), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Early Childhood Conference, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Effective Schools, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Jr. High School: Dedication, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - End Term Dinner, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Executive Board, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - General Membership Meeting, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gross, Irwin M.: Lino Cut, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Individuals: A-L, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Individuals: M-Z, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Jane Addams H.S.: Beauty Inside Out, Inc. - Opening Day, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Levy, Jill: Prints, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Life" Mentoring Program and Workshop, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Lobby Day, 1997, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Meeting with New City Council Members, April 10,1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Middle School Principals' Leadership Conference, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Contact Sheets, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Events with Captions, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Events with Captions, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Series II: Prints For CSA News, 1974-2001
  - Volume 8: Prints, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Volumes 15-19 Prints and Contact Sheets, 1981-1986 (Box 4)
  - Volumes 19-20 Prints and Contact Sheets, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Volumes 21-22 Prints and Contact Sheets, 1987-1989 (Box 6)
  - Volumes 22-23 Prints and Contact Sheets, 1988-1990 (Box 7)
  - Volumes 23-24 Prints, 1989-1991 (Box 8)
  - Volumes 25-34 Prints and Contact Sheets, 1991-2001 (Box 9)
- Series III: Negatives, 1973-1990
  - Convention: Negatives, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Series IV: Negatives For CSA News, 1979-2001
  - Vol. 13: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 13: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Vol. 14: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Vol. 14: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Vol. 15: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Vol. 15: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Vol. 16: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Vol. 16: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Vol. 17: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Vol. 17: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Vol. 18: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Vol. 18: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Vol. 19: Negatives (Folder 1 of 3), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Vol. 19: Negatives (Folder 2 of 3), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Vol. 19: Negatives (Folder 3 of 3), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Vol. 20: Negatives (Folder 1 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Vol. 20: Negatives (Folder 2 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Vol. 20: Negatives (Folder 3 of 3), 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Vol. 21: Negatives (Folder 1 of 4), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 21: Negatives (Folder 2 of 4), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 21: Negatives (Folder 3 of 4), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 21: Negatives (Folder 4 of 4), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 22: Negatives (Folder 1 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 22: Negatives (Folder 2 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 22: Negatives (Folder 3 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 22: Negatives (Folder 4 of 4), 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 23: Negatives (Folder 1 of 3), 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 23: Negatives (Folder 2 of 3), 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 23: Negatives (Folder 3 of 3), 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 24: Negatives (Folder 1 of 4), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 24: Negatives (Folder 2 of 4), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 24: Negatives (Folder 3 of 4), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 24: Negatives (Folder 4 of 4), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 25: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 25: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 26: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Vol. 26: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Vol. 27: Negatives, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 28: Negatives (Folder 1 of 3), 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 28: Negatives (Folder 2 of 3), 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 28: Negatives (Folder 3 of 3), 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 29: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 29: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 30: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 30: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 32: Negatives, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 33: Negatives (Folder 1 of 2), 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 33: Negatives (Folder 2 of 2), 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 34: Negatives, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Series V: Oversized, Undated
  - Oversized: Includes small number panoramic group portraits and photo montages including seventeen photographs (mostly mounted and with text overlays) created for publication in the CSA News., undated (Box 13)